Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在上一集里
It will only respond to the power of a Prime!
只有领袖之力能唤醒它！
Our sensors detected a second Iacon-locator beacon.
探测器发现了另一个铁堡信号！
I'll go.
我去
Smokescreen chooses a vehicle mode with screaming double "38S" on the doors,
烟幕选择的汽车形态 车门上印着一对招摇过市的38
making him an easy target.
很容易被辨识出来
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't more than concerned about Jack's safety.
我没法假装我一点也不担心杰克的安危
The Star Saber,
星辰剑…
a legendary weapon forged by Solus Prime.
卓天越铸造的神兵利器！
We Decepticons now face our darkest hour.
我们霸天虎…迎来了最黑暗的时刻
I am receiving a message.
我收到了一条信息…
From who?
谁发来的？
Alpha Trion.
钛师傅
Forgive me, lord Megatron.
请原谅 威震天陛下
While I do not question the wisdom of our tactical retreat,
属下丝毫不敢质疑您英明的战略性撤退
know that I am fully prepared to lead the troops in a counterattack against the Autobots.
现在 属下已准备好带领人马去反击汽车人了！
Counterattack?
反击？
Perhaps you failed to notice Optimus Prime
你难道没看见
cleave an entire mountain with a single blow.
擎天柱仅一击就切开了整座山吗？
With the Star Saber in his possession,
只要有星辰剑在手
my enemy can obliterate us all with a wave of his hand!
我的宿敌只须抬抬胳膊就能把我们斩尽杀绝！
I must find a way to tip the balance of power back in our favor.
我必须让力量的天平重新向我们倾斜！
Do we not also possess a powerful relic of the ancients?
我们不也拥有一个强大的先祖遗物么？
Indeed... the forge of Solus Prime.
的确如此 那是卓天越之锤
But it is useless, except in the hand of a Prime.
但如果不是握在领袖的手上 那东西就毫无用处…
But I might wield that power
若我有一只领袖之手
if I were to control such a hand!
或许也能支配那神力
Optimus, what is Alpha Trion saying?
擎天柱 钛师傅说了什么？
I wish that I could meet you under better circumstances, Optimus Prime,
我真希望能在更好的境况下与你相会 擎天柱
but I fear that Iacon will not withstand the next Decepticon assault.
但我担心铁堡无法撑过霸天虎的下一轮进攻了
So you speak to me
于是你传话于我
from across the ages.
穿越时空的岁月？
If you are listening to this message,
如果你听到了这则讯息
then I take solace that you now possess the Star Saber.
那么我相信此刻你已经得到了星辰剑
I am certain that you have deduced how these Cybertronian relics and Decepticon weapons
我确信你已经推断出了 这些塞博特恩的遗物和霸天虎的武器
came to be found on such a remote world.
何以出现在如此遥远的世界
Indeed, I transported them there,
没错 是我将它们传送过去的
not so much to keep them far from Megatron's hands,
此举并非是防止它们落入敌手
but to ensure that they reach yours.
而是将它们传授与你…
As you may have long suspected,
正如你长期以来所怀疑的
the Covenant of Primus records events of the future as well as the past.
“原始天尊圣约”不仅记载了过去 还能预示未来
My imperfect understanding of its runes
根据我的不完全解读
affords me a shadowy glimpse of what is to come.
我对未来的景象得以惊鸿一瞥
The Covenant's pages foretold that you, Optimus Prime,
圣约中的一页预言道 你 擎天柱
would journey to the small, but significant planet
将会前往一颗娇小但意义重大的星球
and there engage in a crucial chapter in the war against the Decepticons.
并在那里谱写反霸天虎战争的新篇章
I know neither the nature of the battle
我既无法得知那场战争的前因
nor its outcome, I only hope that
也不晓得后果 我只能寄望于
these relics of the ancients will aid the Autobots in your time of need.
这些先祖遗物能够在你 最需要的时候助汽车人一臂之力
Of utmost importance,
最重要的是
in a few moments,
再过不久
I will launch the last of the relics,
我就会将最后一批遗物传送出去
the most significant and powerful of them all.
这批意义最为重大 同时也是最强大的…
Easy, Optimus.
放松 擎天柱
So, did Alpha try and ask about me?
话说 钛师傅有没有跟我打招呼？
What was the message?
那信息到底讲了什么？
It is paramount that we recover the final four Iacon relics...
找到最后四个铁堡遗物是我们的当务之急
the Omega keys.
它们是“终极之钥”…
Keys?
钥匙？
To what?
能打开什么？
To the regeneration of our home planet.
我们的故乡涅重生的关键…
Earth's Moon is a barren rock, is it not?
地球的月亮不过是一块荒芜的石块 您说是么？
Indeed, Dreadwing.
的确如此 骇翼
But the Moon is not our destination.
但月球并不是我们的目的地
A space bridge?
一座太空桥？
Our very own,
我们独有的太空桥
relocated here after the Autobots discovered its whereabouts on Earth.
自从汽车人在地球上发现了它 我们就将它搬至此处
The dark side of the Moon is hidden from prying human eyes.
月球的背面能够掩人耳目 避开那些喜欢窥探的人类
and, more importantly,
更重要的是
well out of the Autobots' reach.
汽车人也无法到达这里
Come, Dreadwing!
来吧 骇翼！
We shall travel to the one place in the galaxy
我带你去一个地方 就在银河系里
which may provide us with a means of defeating Optimus Prime.
我们将在那里得到能够击败擎天柱的东西！
Pack your gear.
打好行囊
We're going back to Cybertron!
我们就要回塞博特恩了！
Hahahaha. Well, believe it now, Bumblebee.
哈哈哈 信不信由你 大黄蜂！
Civilization at last.
咱终于能回到文明社会了！
But I just got here.
可我才刚初来乍到啊！
Remember oil baths?
还记得油浴吗？
The first thing I'm gonna do planetside is soak for an entire solar cycle.
回去后我要做的第一件事 就是在油里泡上整整一个太阳周期！
Hahaha. I can't wait to tell Miko.
哈哈哈 我都等不及想告诉神子了！
And Jack.
还有…杰克
Can they really revive an entire planet?
那东西真能让整个星球复活吗？
While I am unfamiliar with the lore of these Omega keys,
我并不太清楚这些“终极之钥”的原理
Alpha Trion knew many secrets,
但钛师傅知晓其中的秘密
and the ancients possessed technology
我们的先祖拥有许多神奇的科技
The devastation to our home world is worse than I remember.
故乡比我想象的还要颓败和荒芜…
Curse the Autobots to the pit!
诅咒那些该死的汽车人！
Whatever their function,
尽管还不清楚功能和原理
this much is certain...
但有一件事可以确定
we cannot restore Cybertron without all four Omega keys in our possession.
那就是只有集齐四枚终极之钥 才能让塞博特恩复苏
Which means we can't afford to lose a single one to Megatron.
换言之 我们绝不能让威震天得到任何一枚！
Four sets of coordinates from Alpha Trion remain encrypted.
钛师傅的讯息里还剩下四组加密坐标
It is logical to conclude that each corresponds to the location of one of the Omega keys.
我们可以推断出那就是终极之钥的位置
I must not waver until I decode them all.
我一定会竭尽全力把它们全部破译
The future of our home world depends on it.
故乡的未来就靠它了！
A tomb.
一座古墓！
One known to contain the remains of Primes.
据说这座古墓里长眠着一位元祖领袖！
Please tell me you're not averse to desecration.
拜托 别告诉我你不愿亵渎圣地！
It is just that being in such a place evokes powerful emotions,
我不过是有股情感在心头涌动而已
considering the fate of my twin.
想起了我孪生兄弟的悲惨命运…
Then you should delight in our purpose here,
那你就更应该来到这里
to exact our revenge of Skyquake
为了给天震
and of all our fallen brethren.
和所有牺牲的同胞复仇
You shall require a more practical means of carrying such a blade.
你需要一个合适的方式携带这把利刃…
I feel funny saying this, but
我知道这听起来有些滑稽 但是…
I'm not sure I want to go back.
我不确定我是否真的愿意回去
Who knew we'd ever get so used to our new home?
谁能想到呢 我们已经习惯新家的生活了
Yeah. I don't think I'd ever want to leave Miko.
是啊 我永远都不想离开神子
We've made friends here, family.
我们在这儿交到了朋友…和家人
We could always... text them.
我们不是还能常常…发短信嘛！
Besides,
再说
been fighting for so long, I don't know if I can do anything else.
咱们打了这么久 我都不知道自己还会不会干些别的了
You can go back into construction.
你可以再回去当建筑工人
The power of the ancients may breathe life back into Cybertron's core,
先祖的神力或许能让塞博特恩的核心重焕生机
but our war-ravaged cities will surely require rebuilding.
但被战火摧毁的城市还是需要有人来重建的！
I wouldn't make any travel plans just yet.
我觉得暂时先别想这些旅行计划了
We still have to locate these Omega keys and secure them before the 'Cons do.
咱们还得先找到终极之钥 要赶在虎子之前
Yeah, like that'll be a problem.
那还不是手到擒来啊
Optimus has the Star Saber now.
擎天柱可是有星辰剑在手呢！
Megatron's end is in sight.
威震天的末日指日可待了！
Yes, I can do it, lord Megatron,
我当然可以 威震天陛下…
if you're certain that's what you really want.
如果您确定这就是您想要的
Like nothing I've ever desired before, Doctor.
我比任何时候都坚决 医官
I shall induce stasis.
开始催眠…
No! I wish to bear witness
不！我要亲眼所见
as you attach my new appendage.
你将我的新肢体接驳上来
Coming up.
我开始了
Autobots, I have decoded the first set of the final four coordinates.
汽车人 我已经破译了第一个坐标
Divide into teams in the event
大家分成小组 以防我在第一组回来之前
that I'm able to decode another before the first team returns.
就破译出了第二个坐标
I'm on team one. Who's with me?
我要进第一组！谁想一起来？
I'll go.
我来吧
After you, sir...
您先请 长官
ma'am...
…女士
... commander?
…指挥官？
This should be interesting.
这组合会很有趣…
Uh. Ha ha ha ha hahaha. Yes.
啊 哈哈哈哈 太好了…
At long last, the power of the Primes belongs to me!
终于 领袖的力量现在属于我了！
First one is here.
第一组到达
No locator beacon,
没有信号
which means the relic's still buried
也就是说遗物仍然被埋藏着
right about... there.
就在…那里！
The forge of Solus Prime
卓天越之锤
possesses the ability to create anything from raw material.
拥有能将原材料打造成任何东西的神力？
And in this case,
而现在
said raw material would be a big hunk of Dark Energon.
那原材料可是一大块儿黑暗能量啊
Uh, Arcee, I-I owe you an apology.
那个 阿尔茜 我还欠你一份歉意
I never meant to endanger Jack.
我从来没想过让杰克置身险境
Humans squish easily. I get that now.
人类是很脆弱的 我现在彻底明白这一点了
This isn't just about Jack.
这不光是因为杰克
Team Prime can't afford any casualties,
领袖卫队再也承受不起任何牺牲了
human or bot.
不管是人类还是汽车人！
I've already lost two seasoned partners.
我已经失去两个老搭档了
I don't need a rookie on my scorecard.
我不想在名单上再添一个菜鸟
Not gonna happen.
绝不会的
Elite guardsman's honor.
我以精英卫队的荣誉起誓
Wait. You lost two partners?
慢着 你失去过两个搭档？
You have decoded the next set of Iacon coordinates.
你又破译了一组铁堡遗物的坐标？
Excellent work, Soundwave.
干得漂亮 声波！
Ha. Nice of the humans to pile all these rocks on top of our relic, huh?
哈 人类还挺热衷把这些巨石堆到咱们的遗物上 是吧？
Pretty much spells things out, doesn't it?
不言而喻 是吧？
Come on. Help me move this.
来 帮我移开这个！
The ancient humans must have thought the Omega key was a gift from the gods.
古代人类八成把终极之钥当成众神赐予的礼物了
And, in a sense, they weren't wrong.
某种意义上讲 他们没错
The relic... now!
快点 交出遗物
Two against one. We can take him.
二打一 我们能搞定他
Ratchet, ground bridge, now!
救护车 打开环陆桥 快！
Smokescreen!
烟幕！
What manner of treasure did Iacon send us this time?
这次铁堡送来的又是怎样的宝物？
I would slice you in two right now...
我可以现在就把你切成两半
but I need you to deliver a message.
但我还想要你传个口信
Tell Optimus Prime that if he wants this relic,
告诉擎天柱 他要是想要遗物
he must come and claim it himself!
就亲自来抢！
And then Smokescreen was just... gone...
接着烟幕就…消失了
like he turned to dust.
好像烟消云散一般
Poor kid.
可怜的娃
Arcee, do not blame yourself.
阿尔茜 别太自责
It could just as easily have been you.
当时你也命在旦夕
I say we go claim a piece of Megatron's miserable, metal hide!
要我说我们这就去扒下威震天一块皮下来！
No. We have already lost another one of our own today.
不行 今天我们已经失去了一位战友了
I will not risk more lives.
我不能再让任何人冒险
Given what Arcee witnessed,
根据阿尔茜的所见
it stands to reason that Megatron now possesses might to equal the Star Saber,
可以推断威震天拥有一件与星辰剑威力相当的武器
which means only I have a chance of recovering the Omega key.
也就是说 只有我有可能夺回终极之钥
The fate of Cybertron rests upon its retrieval.
塞博特恩的命运全指望它了
Whether Megatron knows it or not.
不管威震天明不明白
Claim your prize, Optimus.
来拿你的战利品吧 擎天柱
If you can.
只要你拿得到
By the Allspark, Megatron.
火种源在上 威震天
What have you done?!
你做了什么？
This.
这个吗？
I find it affords me certain advantages,
它为我赢得了一些优势
such as the use of the Forge of Solus Prime.
比如使用卓天越之锤
My first creation,
这是我的第一件作品
fashioned from the very blood of Unicron.
以宇宙大帝之血铸就
I call it the Dark Star Saber...
我称之为暗黑星辰剑
slayer of Primes, if you will.
你也可以称它 屠戮领袖之剑！
At last we take our rightful places, Optimus.
最终我们还是接受了命运的安排 擎天柱
As gods, wielding the power of the cosmos!
逆天成神！我们挥舞着宇宙的力量！
I am but a soldier, Megatron,
我只不过是个战士 威震天
and you are a prisoner of your own twisted delusions!
而你 只不过是被自我扭曲的妄想所囚禁的狂徒！
My Dark Star Saber has tasted one spark tonight.
我的暗黑星辰剑今晚已经啜饮过一个火种的鲜血
It still thirsts for that of a Prime!
它还渴望着吞噬一个领袖的生命！
And so it ends, just as I envisioned,
大幕将落 正如我所预见的一样！
with your head beside my new trophy.
我要用你的头颅来祭我的战利品！
Oh, you mean this?
哦 你是说这个？
Finders keepers.
谁找到归谁！
Smokescreen, fall back!
烟幕 退后！
Ratchet, ground bridge!
救护车 打开环陆桥！
No!
不！
Missed us.
没打中
Run, Optimus, run!
逃吧 擎天柱 尽管逃吧！
Those trinkets from Iacon will not save you,
这些铁堡的小玩具救不了你的
not when I now possess the power to tear this world apart!
因为现在我拥有了能斩断整个世界的力量！
Smokescreen?!
烟幕？
And Omega key number one.
以及第一个终极之钥！
But... how? I mean, I saw you...
可 这是怎么…我是说 我亲眼看见…
I, uh, decided to borrow the Phase shifter.
我 呃 之前又“借”走了相位仪！
Again?
又一次！
Good thing, too.
幸亏我拿了
The wave from the blast hit me like a wrecking ball.
那阵冲击波简直像铁球一样砸在我身上！
The impact must have activated the shifter.
一定是那冲击激活了相位仪
I don't know how long I was unconscious,
我不知道昏迷了多久
but when I made my way back outside,
不过当我好不容易出来的时候
Optimus and Megatron were deep in an epic throwdown.
擎天柱和威震天正在进行一场史诗般的战斗！
I waited for the right moment to make my move.
我只是瞅准时机 做了该做的事…
You're learning.
你有进步
So, can I keep it?
那么我能留着它吗？
I mean, it is really working out for me.
我是说 这玩意儿对我来说太好使了！
Fine, fine.
好吧 好吧
Yes! Signature weapon!
好哎！我也有专属武器了！
You got yours. Optimus lost his.
你得到了你的武器 擎天柱却失去了他的
The balance of power shifted again.
力量的天平又向另一方倾斜了
While he may have wielded the power of the ancients for only one day,
虽说他仅能使用一天先祖留下的神力
Optimus does not require it to be the mightiest of warriors.
但擎天柱不依靠外力 仍旧是最伟大的战士